易考范文十一
In the ridiculous cartoon,
a man is peering into a telescope with great interest,
a half-naked woman emerging in his mind.
Behind him a long queue of men are waiting for their turn in eager anticipation.
A couple of words—certain social surveys—can be seen on the telescope.
The cartoon aims to highlight a social aspect
that a bundle of surveys pay excessive attention to personal privacy.
Who is to blame for the phenomenon?
In my opinion, the media are mainly responsible for it.
A good social survey is supposed to provide insight into
some general matters of the society and appeal to people for concern about them.
However, the media, who conduct most social surveys,
are more interested in privacy-related issues than in widespread problems.
Trying to please the public with claptrap and gain fame,
the media actually mislead the public, and, purposely sometimes,
infringe on citizens' right of privacy.
As far as I am concerned,
the solution lies in the joint effort of the authorities and the media.
On the one hand, it is essential that
the authorities formulate laws and regulations to ensure
that individual information is kept confidential.
On the other hand, the media must strengthen their sense of social responsibility,
directing the public’s attention to issues of more significance.